Hello friends, my name is Banay and you are
watching Ban Tech, so today I am going to
tell you how to fill the death claim
form of AAA Bank.
How can you fill the death claim form of AAA Bank? I am going to
tell you in full detail, so
let's start. You can see here is the
application form for this
claim. If any account holder dies,
whose account is in ICICI Bank, then
their legal heir will have to fill this form
and the account of the deceased will be
transferred in your name
or you will get it. So I will
tell you in detail how you have to
fill this form of AAA Bank. Let's
start filling the form. So here
you can see the application for death
form to be fed of one account or nomination
and MO is IRS and any one survivor. Okay, so it is
applicable in these two cases. Okay, so
here you can see to the
branch manager of AAA Bank. Here you have to
write the name of the branch and then here
You have to give the bank address here,
okay, from here you have to
write your name, the one who is claiming, if there are
multiple claims, if there are multiple legal heirs, that
means he is making multiple claims, then here
both their names and addresses will be there,
okay, so I am giving my details here
and here you can see,
dear sir, the name of the dist account of the Mr./Smt. who has
expired, I am
writing any unknown name here, okay,
then the account number has to be written,
okay, the advice of the device of
Mr./Smt. whoever has expired, their name has to be
written here, and she holds the
above account in your branch, the account is in the
name of whoever the debt is, their name has to be written,
and here you can see, you have to tick
if there is nomination, then
you have to fill this part, okay, I am holding
registered nomination in this account
by the name of the one who is claiming, his name,
son/daughter, whatever it is, okay, of those who are
theirs  In the receipt form, you have to write the address here and
then the second part which is
nomination in this account is in the name of
minor by the name of okay
if the nominee is a minor means below 18 years of age
okay then this part will have to be filled
so I am skipping this part
okay and in the C part here
you can see please settle the balance
in the account in the nominee name okay
requesting you to delete the name of the decided
person and continue the account in the name of all other
joint account holders with the same mode
of operation okay in the C part it is saying that to
delete the name of the decided person
and continue it, joint account
holder or single account holder whoever it is with the same
mode of operation means brother and
survivor any one survivor okay the
account will start working in all these modes okay
if there is a nominee and here you
can see we submit photocopy of the following
documents together with the original  You will have to
take the original and photocopy, there will be
verification and here you
can see the date certificate issued by, from
wherever you have got it issued, its address will be there, like
mine, I got it from the Municipal Office,
so here I am
writing Municipal Office, okay and then
whatever address is there here, you will have to give
identity proof in nomination
cases, like Aadhar card, PAN card, whatever it is,
Voter ID, whatever it is, here you
can give KYC document, again you will have to give Aadhar
card, okay, we
note to give other document required by
you like stamp receipt for the amount to be paid,
in due course, okay and
in the third point,
if you have to give additional document, like legal heir certificate or
any document, if IC asks for it, then
you will have to give it here, okay
and if the account holder is an ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance policy
holder, then you will have to give all this  You will have to give it to the claimant,
okay, copy of policy document, welcome
kit, then copy of date certificate issued
by local authority, whichever is municipal office,
okay, and claimant and nominee current
address and photo identity proof have to be
given here, like Aadhar card, PAN card, voter
ID, whatever it is, you can give it here,
okay, if the claimant is multiple, then there will be
multiple signatures here, if it is single, then
you have to sign here,
okay, and you have to
skip this part, you will get this slip,
okay, to be fed in by branch
step, and the second part which is application
form, disclaimer, to be fed at the time of
conversion to state account, okay, if you
want to convert the account, then you will have to
fill this form here, from
here you have to write your name and
then give the address, and here pay to the
branch manager, Aaaa Bank Limited, branch,
then give the date, dear sir, dist account letter,
Mr./Smt., whoever is the payer, their
name, then the account number will be of the account holder,
okay, the ID of the person who is making the claim  Their
name will be there and then the relationship has to be given and
here the relationship has to be given like father
daughter whatever it is, okay of Mr./Smt. whatever has been
given, okay of the device of
Mr./Smt. here again the
name of the account holder will be there on date and she
holds the account at branch has to be given and
following are the legal heir and nominee for the
account of the deceased and here the
name of whoever is making the claim will be there, okay and
then the father's name and address have to be
filled like this, if multiple claims are being made then
you can give it here by filling it in the same way,
okay and here submit the
photocopy of death certificate issued by,
whichever death certificate has been issued here, whether it
is the municipal office or from where you have
brought it, its details will be here, okay
along with the original, you people have to
take the original also and we authorize the bank to
modify the account name as state of let, whatever it
is, their name will be there, all
pipeline flows future  Credit in the name
of the system with be credited and here
you can read all these details once,
okay, if you people if the account holder
is an ICI Prudential Life Insurance policy holder then all this will have to be given to him,
okay and here you people have to
sign the person who is making the claim, if there are
multiple claims then there will be multiple signatures
here, okay and the acknowledgement
receipt which is here, this branch top will
give you the application form to be used
for cases other than nomination, IRS and any
one and survivor case, okay, for all these cases
you will have to submit this application, it is the
same here, here the form means you
people have to write your name, then
write the address, then here the branch manager, here
you people have to write the branch name,
whoever is the account holder, Mr. or Mrs. their
name will be there, their account number will be there, okay,
advise the device of Mr. and Mrs. whoever is the
debtor, their name will be there, on date has to be
given, okay, yes and she holds the above
account in your branch, we shall be glad if
you please  Settle the balance amount in the dispute
depositor account to the following. Okay, the
name of the person who is claiming will be the son and
daughter of whoever has paid. Okay,
deciding at, address has to be given here. If there are
multiple claims, then
you can give another one here as well. And then here you will have to
give the photocopy and original document. Okay, the caste
certificate issued by whichever office
details will be there. Succession certificate which is a
legal certificate. You will have to give
affidavit. You will have to give letter of
disclaimer. You will have to give letter of indenture
and letter of administration.
Okay, I will tell you all this in a short while.
If that account holder is an ISI
Prudential Life Insurance policy
holder, then all his details will be copy
of policy document, copy of death
certificate, claimant and nominee's current
address and photo identity proof. Okay,
and then the signature of the person who is claiming will be there.
Okay, if there are multiple claims, then
you have to do multiple signatures here.  It will be required,
okay, and the
branch staff will give you the customer acknowledgement receipt. So, now I am going to
tell you about the letter of disclaimer.
In the letter of disclaimer, you will
need the signature of the legal heir, okay,
so that you are authorizing the bank to transfer the
money of the deceased account holder to one
person. So, here
you can see "To the Branch Manager,
Aaaa Bank Limited" here you have to write the branch name,
then give the date. Dear Sir, here
you have to write the account number of the deceased
account holder, okay, in the name of the person in
whose name it is and write the balance. And the
name of the deceased account holder has to be
written here. Okay, I will write the following legal heir
of the late Mr./Smt. Whoever has made the payment,
their name has to be written. You have to write the name of the person in whose
name you are getting the transfer done.
If there are multiple claimants, then
you can give one name, okay, if you are single, then you
can write your name, okay, and here you have to
write the name of the legal heir, age and
relationship.
What were you guys with the decision, like son, father, mother,
whoever it is, you can write it here, okay,
and then here you have to get the signature of the legal heir,
okay, and sign before
me, son of whoever it is, you can write it here,
here you have to write the address, on
which day you have submitted it, at what
time you can write it here,
then you will need witnesses, this thing has to be kept in
mind, you can take one or two witnesses, if the witness is
of the bank then it is
very good, if not then any other person will be fine,
and where the
star mark is given here, you
can see, here it is a savings account,
this is an ID account or an FD account,
whatever it is, you have to write it here, okay, so
this is the meaning of the star mark, and the
acknowledgement receipt from the claimant for
receipt of funds, this is the receipt,
you people do not have to do anything in it, so this is
a type of receipt, okay, you
people do not have to do anything in it, then only you  People have to
write the place date and then
taking the revenue stamp you have to sign the
claimant okay and this is what you will get
Receipt and Declaration
in Case Funds are Settled in Favour of a Minor
if it is a minor then this part has to be filled
I am skipping this and
here you can see the innity format to be
stamped as n innity stamp duty to
ours per applicable Stamp Act and letter
of innity with respect to payment of
balance in the dispute consent and account without
production of legal representation okay
so this is useful if you are
not able to present legal representation
then this one will be useful for you
okay so here you can see
in the first part insert here names of the
hirer of the dispute to home payment is done okay
here you have to write the name of the hirer
which is the legal hire okay to whom the
payment will be made in consideration of your
paying  And agree to us to pay me and us, whatever it is,
here you people have to write the name in
whose name the payment is being made and and if there are
multiple claimants then you people have to
write single name, okay and here you people have to
write the rupees and the credit of account
number has to be written here in whose account the
credit of is here, here is the savings account, RD
account, whatever it is, you people have to
write it here and then give the account number, okay, in
the name of whose name the money is, the
name of the person who has died will be there, okay, since disease
without production of letter of
administration and succession certificate, so
this thing has to be kept in mind, if you people are
not giving any legal representation then this has to be
filled, okay then state here the
names of the legal heirs of the dist including those who
signed letter of authority,
okay and in the second part here you people
can see, state here the name of the heirs
of the dist including those who signed letter
of authority, okay, the
details of those who have signed will be there and here is the address  It will remain
and here you can see the state her
name of the securities, whichever securities
you have to give here and all the
legal age there is, their
signature will be here and two securities have to be brought,
generally two securities are asked for, okay
witness and here the date has to be written, place has to be
written and then here the address of
witnesses, name and addresses of the witnesses have to be taken
here, the signature of the witness and the
format of the Affi debit should be something like this,
okay and here you people have to
write your name and if there are multiple claims,
you can write here, okay, here you have to
write the name and date of the one which has expired, on which day it had expired, where it had
expired, okay and for how many years
you people know, which one has expired,
you people have to write the years here, okay
then if there are multiple claims, then the name is
given here, option, okay, if it is single then
your name will be there, then age has to be written, then
relationship with the deceased,
what is your relationship with whoever has died, okay
and here you  People have to write the branch name,
then the branch name and here you will have to go to the judge and
magistrate or the notary,
you have to get all
this written by them on a stamp paper,
okay and after getting the signature and seal entered,
you have to get the signature done here,
so this was the format of affidavit but of Aaa Bank
and I have told you in detail
how you can make a death claim
in Aaa Bank, so if this video
is useful for you, please like, share, comment and
subscribe to my channel Bentech, thank you.